Six reasons why the west was wild.
Young Guns is a western, action, adventure film directed by Christopher Cain.
A group of young gunmen, led by Billy the Kid, become deputies to avenge
the murder of the rancher who became their benefactor.
But when Billy takes their authority too far, they become the hunted.
William H. Bonney, played by Emilio Estevez.
Doc Scurlock, played by Kiefer Sutherland.
Chavez y Chavez, played by Lou Diamond Phillips.
Dick Brewer, played by Charlie Sheen.
Dirty Steve Stephens, played by Dermot Mulroney.
Charley Bowdre, played by Casey Siemaszko.
Young Guns is a 1988 American Western action film directed and
produced by Christopher Cain and written by John Fusco.
The film depicts a heavily fictionalized version of the actions of Billy the Kid and
the Regulators during the Lincoln County War, in New Mexico in 1877–78.
It stars Emilio Estevez as Billy, and Kiefer Sutherland, Lou Diamond Phillips, Estevez's brother
Charlie Sheen, Dermot Mulroney, and Casey Siemaszko as the other Lincoln County Regulators.
The supporting cast features Terence Stamp, Terry
O'Quinn, Brian Keith, and Jack Palance.
The first film to be produced by Morgan Creek Productions, Young Guns received mixed reviews, with critics polarised over its inaccuracies and story, despite
praise for the performances, and opened at number one at the US box office and eventually grossed $56 million against an $11-million budget.
Because of the film's cast, it is often associated with
the "Brat Pack" set of 1980s actors.
A sequel, Young Guns II, was released in 1990, with the
principal cast reprising their roles.
A third film is currently in development.
The film explores themes of sheriff, bounty hunter,
corruption, deputy sheriff, anti hero.
The tone is lighthearted.